210-788-9667

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Certified network engineer with 20 years of experience working in TS-SCI environments. A veteran problem solver, able to analyze situations and create a strategy to accomplish the goal. Forward thinking, gained computer programming skills and cybersecurity expertise to not only secure the network but to be ready for the move into the future with software defined networks. Skill supported by an associate of applied science in Electronic Systems Technology, CISSP, CCNP, ITIL v3, CompTIA Secure Infrastructure Specialist.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS OBTAINED		
CCNP	CISSP CompTIA A+, Security+, Network	ITIL Foundation +
	PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	

11/2017 to Present - InfoSec Manager, 625th ACOMS

Lackland AFB, Texas

- Managed security team overseeing 256 personnel enforcing a mandatory access control system for a Top Secret Secure Compartmented Information facility (SCIF).
- Performed site security evaluations and presented monthly status briefings to senior leadership. Reported security violations and recommended action plans for implementation along with counseling management on regulatory requirements.
- Initiated background investigations, authenticated information access, and oversaw security education and training awareness program.

10/2016 to 11/2017 - Regional IT Manager, AFN Korea

Camp Humphreys, Korea

- Directed 10-man IT section supporting five studio locations across Korea; enforcing cybersecurity standards and maintaining radio, TV broadcast & network services while achieving a 99% up-time rate.
- Coordinated four locations and installed \$600K in IT equipment for a new facility as project manager for a short notice radio broadcast center relocation. Project came in under deadline and accomplished with zero broadcast interruption. Effort led to being award AFN Pacific 2017 Project of the Year.
- Develop a Radio Reader program for on air personalities by leveraging Microsoft Access. Implemented controls for statistical data and writing a maintenance guide for future administrators.

01/2016 to 10/2016 - Lead IT Project Manager, 49th CS

Holloman AFB, New Mexico

- Oversaw \$100K network security contract. Which led to the elimination of 4.7K high threat network vulnerabilities.
- Project lead for CM6 VOIP Call Manager; managed workforce and enforced contract guidelines resulting in modernizing voice capabilities for 6.2K employees.

03/2015 to 1/2016 – IT Section Manager, 49th CS

Holloman AFB, New Mexico

- Supervised 10 personnel on an inspection prep team of 408 nodes eradicating 47.3K vulnerabilities resulted in the section earning highest rating for the 2015 Cyber Readiness Inspection.

01/2013 to 03/2015 - IT Section Manager, 49th AMXS

Holloman AFB, New Mexico

- Managed 50 IT personnel for the Remote Piloted Aircraft training squadron leading to the certification of 811 pilots and 31.4K missions flown. Efforts led to earning employee of the year for 2015
- Organized Security+ certification training; coordinated instructor travel, site prep, and organization saving the Air Force \$30K in outside training costs.

01/2010 to 01/2013 - Lead Network Engineer, 606th ACS

Spangdahlem, Germany

- Managed mobile infrastructure team deploying in support of worldwide US & North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) operations.
- Deployed to Kirkuk, Iraq as IT section lead for a five-member team; managing IT support for air traffic controllers executing 13K combat missions. Awarded Team of the Month.

EDUCATION

- Working toward Bachelor's in Network Operations and Security with WGU
- Electronic Systems Technology, A.A.S.

TRAINING

- Cisco Programming for Network Engineers Course (PRNE)
- Learning VMware vSphere 6.5
- Fiber & Copper Network Installations Courses
- Electronic Computer and Switching Systems Technicians Course, Distinguished Graduate
- Electrical Engineer Technician Course
- Communications Electronics QA Evaluator Course